<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dulguun Gantumur</title>
    <link>https://dulguun.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dulguun Gantumur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 22:05:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dulguun.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Turko-Mongolic Links and Correspondences</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/turko_mongolic/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 22:05:42 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/turko_mongolic/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/turko_mongolic/ -&lt;p&gt;It is clear to those who have either studied both a Turkic and Mongolic language or has an interest in linguistic, especially historical, that there is a deep connection between these language families. Personally, my language learning journey of Azerbaijani has already many common vocabulary between it and Mongolian, despite the short length of my study. Turkic countries generally seem to be aware of this fact, but Mongolia largely seems to be unaware of their linguistic connection to the Turkic world.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Bringing this connection to public awareness would lend strong legitimacy to a greater cooperation between Mongolia and Central Asian countries, especially cooperation based on Inner Asian pan-nationalism, commonly referred as Turanism. Below is an extensive discussion of the technical linguistic connections between Turkic and Mongolic languages, then followed by how they may practically affect how Turanism is received in Central Asian countries.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;linguistics&#34;&gt;Linguistics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;loans&#34;&gt;Loans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The linguistic connections between Mongolic and Turkic is primarily based on two properties common to both language families: vocabulary, and grammar structure. Common vocabulary is the easiest to explain on the surface but also something one can dive quite deep into. Most common type of shared vocabulary represented are Turkic loans into Mongolic, and these words have been continually borrowed over the course of several hundred years, although there loans into Turkic from Mongolic as well, especially on the eastern varieties.. Because of this, the Turkic loans in Mongolic can be divided into several layers, pre-Proto-Mongolic, Proto-Mongolic, and post-Mongol Invasions. The deeper one goes in the layer, the more difficult it becomes to identify a word as a cognate.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
For example, cognates in the pre-Proto-Mongolic stage, despite looking completely unrelated, such as Proto-Mongolic *&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;čilagun&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; ‘stone’ and Proto Turkic *&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;tiāĺ&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; id. are actually related. To make sense of it as a cognate, several overlapping processes must understood. First, is that rather than Common Turkic languages, which nearly every modern Turkic language is, pre-Proto-Mongolic languages extensively borrowed from Oghur Turkic languages, which stand out in contrast to even other Turkic languages. Oghur Turkic langauges are characterized by *&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;l&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; in place of *&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;š&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; in Common Turkic. As a result, the -l- in the Proto-Mongolic word unexpectedly corresponds to -š- in most modern Turkic languages. Secondly, every Mongolic language exhibits palatalization of alveolar stops (t, d) in front of ‘i’. So *&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;ti-&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; in Proto-Turkic corresponds to *&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;či-&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; in Mongolic. With later developments in the languages applied, the modern reflexes of these words turns out to be “čuluu” in Modern Mongolian, and “taş” in Turkish. Related, yet completely different.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
In contrast to these deep early loanwords, the words of the later stages becomes easily identifiable by lay people, sometimes even resulting in almost the exact same pronunciation. These cognates are extensive due to the incorporation of Turkic tribes into the Mongol Empire, during and after which these loans were taken. Since these loans were between Common Turkic languages and Mongolic languages, their modern reflexes still strongly resemble each other. Some extremely obvious cognates are&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mongolic “&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;tani-&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;” ‘to recognize, to know’ &amp;lt; Common Turkic “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;tanï-&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;” id.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mongolic “&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;alima&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;” ‘apple’ &amp;lt; Turkic “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;alma&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;” id.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turkic “&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;aral&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;” ‘island’ &amp;lt; Mongolic “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;aral&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;” id.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;altaic&#34;&gt;Altaic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond these loanwords, let us discuss the obvious controversy of the Altaic language family, or the Transeurasian languages as it has been referred to recently. While the fact that there were heavy borrowings between these languages of Eurasia, some linguists propose that looking deeper into them reveals a genetic relationship between them. The language families often included in Altaic are Turkic, Mongolic, and Tungusic languages of  Siberia and Manchuria. Koreanic and Japonic are sometimes includes as well. This grouping is often controversial since the word comparisons between these languages often rely on exaggerated semantic shifts and dubious sound correspondences.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Altaic languages, should they be accepted by the mainstream academic opinion, would certain yield great credibility to Turanic ideas since it would be providing academic support to a common origin between Turkic and Mongolic cultures. Many groups adopt this position of accepting Altaic languageswith some variations as a valid grouping to promote their version of pan-Nationalism. The ideology of the Jobbik party of Hungary, a Hungarian nationalist party, takes the position that “Uralic people”, including the Hungarian nation, originate from a wider Uralo-Altaic people. This is used to lend support to policies favoring greater connection with Turkey and Central Asian countries.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
But, for Turko-Mongolic relations, whether or not their language families share a common origin is not as important. The fact that Turkic and Mongolic groups have had contact with each other and intercultural exchanges is already commonly accepted by mainstream academia. Genetic relations in the linguistic or the biological sense does not have to be the main pillar of Turanism, but may serve as a supporting beam. Having such deep cultural and linguistic connections is already evidence enough to lend support to Turanic cooperation between these two societies.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;nationalism&#34;&gt;Nationalism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the linguistic connections between the two language families established, these facts must now be properly deployed to politically legitimize Turko-Mongolic nationalism. .&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/mono/10.4324/9780203987551/studies-turkic-mongolic-linguistics-edmund-bosworth-gerard-clauson%22%3EClauson&#34;&gt;https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/mono/10.4324/9780203987551/studies-turkic-mongolic-linguistics-edmund-bosworth-gerard-clauson&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Clauson&lt;/a&gt;, Gerard. Studies in Turkic and Mongolic linguistics. Routledge, 2005.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/download/54600439/TURKIC_ELEMENTS.pdf%22%3ER&#34;&gt;https://www.academia.edu/download/54600439/TURKIC_ELEMENTS.pdf&amp;quot;&amp;gt;R&lt;/a&gt;óna-Tas, András. “Turkic elements in Khitan.” unter dem Bodhi-Baum: Festschrift für Klaus RÖHRBORN anlässlich des 80 (2019): 293-301.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/462606/Mongolic_%C4%8Dilagun_Turkic_t%C4%81%C5%A1%22%3EKempf&#34;&gt;https://www.academia.edu/462606/Mongolic_%C4%8Dilagun_Turkic_t%C4%81%C5%A1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Kempf&lt;/a&gt;, Béla. “Mongolic čilagun: Turkic tāš.” Turkic Languages 14 (2010): 103-112.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/mono/10.4324/9780203987919/mongolic-languages-juha-janhunen%22%3ESch&#34;&gt;https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/mono/10.4324/9780203987919/mongolic-languages-juha-janhunen&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Sch&lt;/a&gt;önig, Claus. “Turko-Mongolic relations.” The Mongolic languages 403 (2003): 19.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ibtimes.com/strange-bedfellows-hungarian-far-right-jobbik-party-embraces-muslim-nations-seeks-eurasian-ideal.%22%3E&#34;&gt;https://www.ibtimes.com/strange-bedfellows-hungarian-far-right-jobbik-party-embraces-muslim-nations-seeks-eurasian-ideal.&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Hungarian Far-Right Jobbik Party Embraces Muslim Nations.” 2013. International Business Times. December 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/turko_mongolic/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Benefits of Language Self-Study</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/self_study/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 21:56:11 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/self_study/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/self_study/ -&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between undertaking self study in languages and taking language classes. Language classes have a teacher and this teacher is the person who structures the lesson plan for the students. Each session, the teacher goes over material and assigns homework for the students, rinse and repeat. Perhaps there are fun games and exercises to practice the material every once in a while. This has several effects which may hinder the typical student who takes such a class, but let&amp;rsquo;s go over the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the structure means that there is no time wasted planning out a lesson and what to learn, it has already been handled by the instructor. Secondly, there is always someone to ask questions about the language, whatever it may be, and typically since the instructor is a native specifically trained to deeply understand the language&amp;rsquo;s properties, they will be able to answer it. Finally, there is a class of other students who are also going over the same exact material, creating a sense of community and even new friendships which some may find valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are some downsides which may not be obvious at a first glance. The pace at which a language class moves will always be at the pace of the slowest student since if there is missed material then it must be explained properly before moving on to the next lesson by the fact that language lessons build on the previous lessons. This makes movement of the class painfully slow depending on the class size. Even if the class size is one: a private lesson, there is a problem with the lesson/homework cycle. It sets up a clear delineation for the student for what and how much material should be learned. Once the homework is done, there is nothing more, since moving ahead is discouraged when there is already a premade timeline with the structured lessons plans already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might all still be fine for most students. However, there is another option that is more talked about than actually done. That of self study. Self studying is a skill that takes practice but is an infinitely more rewarding option than only taking language classes. First let&amp;rsquo;s go over the benefits and drawbacks of this option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest benefit as well as downside is that the language learning speed is entirely determined by the student. If a student is already familiar with features of a language, they are entirely free to skip ahead and learn what is actually difficult for them. Or if they are particularly good at memorizing vocabulary, they are free to learn more words at a faster pace, rather than wait for the instructor to help a classmate to recall the same words. It removes the hypothetical speed limit imposed by an instructor&amp;rsquo;s structure, instead learn at one&amp;rsquo;s own pace. It is obvious that this is clearly not the best option for everyone, since learning at one&amp;rsquo;s own pace may end up being significantly slower than what would&amp;rsquo;ve been achieved with a proper structure and the instructor&amp;rsquo;s demand for homework. But in my personal view, if that is indeed the case that one cannot learn a language without the stick of an instructor, then perhaps they are not internally motivated enough to achieve genuine success in the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of structure, this is also entirely determined by the student. No one learns languages the exact same way, yet the class system is forced to do so since it is unable to accommodate each student. A flexible structure allows the learner to experiment with various techniques for planning out a lesson for themselves and decide what is best for them, instead of an instructor deciding how the best way to teach is. Here again what is an advantage for some is a downside for others. A flexible structure may simply lead to no structure filled with random language apps or too many textbooks. It is easy to fall into this trap, and is a common experience for many self-learners starting out in language learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also cheaper. No need to pay for an instructor to take their time teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supposed benefits of a classroom setting can be easily replaced as well. For example, the instructor is a person who can answer any question that one may have about a question, but there are hundreds of people online who either have answered the exact same question already or are ready to answer out of sheer goodwill. Similarly, one is never truly alone in learning a language, there is always a community out there focused around either learning that particular language, or simply for the love of language learning itself, such as our Language Cafe. They can just as easily fill the role of community and friendship. Not to mention, there are many guides out there for self-learners who have given their thoughts on how to structure a language learning plan, so nobody starts off completely rock bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;suggestions&#34;&gt;Suggestions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some pointers to make the self learning journey easier that I found out from my personal experience. Firstly, focus on one material as the main source for language learning. This can be an online textbook or a comprehensive language learning app. Personally I would not recommend Duolingo though it can be done because of how sluggish and boring the lessons on the app tend to be, which counteracts all the benefits mentioned before about the potential speed. Other apps can play a supplementary role to the primary source, this can be apps focused on a specific skill such as Anki for word memorization, or Clozemaster for sentence mining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second pointer is to make sure to always look for materials to listen to. Ideally the primary source used should have a listening component, but if not, make sure to allocate time specifically for listening practice. It is a skill which classrooms and instructors provide readily since there is always a native or near native speaker during classroom time, but it is not guaranteed in a self study setting. A good exercise is to try to listen for comprehension without looking at the text, to specifically target that skill. It is shocking how much becomes incomprehensible without a transcription to help out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, speak away without embarrassment. While listening comprehension becomes more difficult to practice outside the classroom, speaking becomes infinitely more fun and easier to practice. Take advantage of the fact that there is nobody else listening by speaking everything out loud and practice getting used to speaking the language. I would suggest spending more time on correct pronunciation at the very start and not being lazy with it, because a bad pronunciation combined with a lot of speech practice solidifies the bad pronunciation. On the other hand, starting out with good pronunciation just means that with each lesson, one becomes more comfortable at speaking correctly. Shadowing is a great technique for practicing speaking that should probably only be done at home when others aren&amp;rsquo;t looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully now the topic of self studying a language does not seem as daunting. It takes practice to fully develop the discipline necessary to stick to a language without a pre-made structure to simply follow, as well as time to find and develop the right form of personal language study technique. However, in the end, it may turn out to be the decision that takes the language learning experience to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/self_study/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Illiberal Democracy in Hungary</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/illiberalhungary/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 21:08:36 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/illiberalhungary/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/illiberalhungary/ -&lt;p&gt;Hungary has experienced democratic backsliding in recent years, which stands out since it is a country in the EU, located at the center of Europe, and surrounded by strong democracies. Yet somehow, a strong wave of right-wing parties who openly declare themselves to be against “liberal democracy” has taken hold in the country, in stark contrast to the standard seen in the European Union. The prime minister of this party, Viktor Orbán declared that “illiberal democracy” is the country’s future, which led some to question what exactly this entails, and how such a concept has taken hold in a country surrounded by democracies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper explores the origins of illiberalism as stemming from the socialist time period, the development of a paternalist political culture, as well as unique events in Hungary’s history that led to an illiberal democracy in Hungary. Second, the paper explores what exactly an “illiberal democracy” means and how it has worked out in Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;origins-of-illiberal-democracy&#34;&gt;Origins of Illiberal Democracy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origins of illiberalism in Hungary begin from its socialist although some might argue that it originates even earlier from its lengthy history as a monarchy. During the socialist era, as a result of its policies, social equity was kept relatively stable and even. Another feature of the socialist system was the strong state institutions which built a culture of a demand for a strong state, even if at the same time, they distrusted the state. This built up a strong paternalist culture in Hungary and set the expectations they had for the state. 2017 polls in Hungary indicated that nearly one-third of Hungarians perceived there to be no fundamental differences between any political systems such as a “democracy” or “dictatorship”. (Bıró-Nagy 2017, p. 34)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, many Hungarians were hopeful about their transition to democracy. A major expectation that the Hungarians had for democracy was economic prosperity. Polls from the start of democratization in Hungary indicated that Hungarians believed that economic prosperity was just as important of a feature of democracy as free elections were. (Bıró-Nagy 2017, p. 34) However, these expectations would be shattered when after two decades of capitalism and liberal democracy in the Hungary resulted in widespread unemployment and a new class of plutocrats instead. Polls indicate that in 2017, nearly 72% of Hungarians believed that that the country was worse off than under socialism. (Bıró-Nagy 2017, p. 31)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the stage set, several political and economic crises finally pushed the right-wing Fidesz government to become mainstream in Hungarian politics. This started off with the high degree of political polarization between the con- servative and socialist parties in Hungary. The private recording of the socialist party’s prime minister admitting in a profanity riddled speech that they had done nothing for the country and lied for years straight about the state of the country. (Magyar 2010) This led to the disillusionment of many of the Hungarian public and pushed them to vote for the opposition party, Fidesz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;definition&#34;&gt;Definition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prime minister of Fidesz, Viktor Orbán, declared in a speech in 2010, that liberalism had failed in Hungary, and that their government was that of “illiberal democracy.” The exact definition of what exactly this terms entailed is confusing, but some clues are to be found in Orbán’s own speeches and the voters. Looking at what the voters understand the term to be, they say it’s a “rejection of the last 20 years of post-communism.” (Buzogány 2017, p. 1314)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Orbán himself, he states that Western liberalism is not suited for the culture of Hungarians, which is that of authoritarianism and collectivism. A major criticism he had of Western liberal democracy was that it had not led to the prosperity of the general population, and only worked to benefit the few, or the individual. In this way, illiberal democracy has a strong populist core to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another inspiration for Orbán’s conception of an illiberal democracy is what he terms the “Asian model&amp;quot;. This includes countries such as China, Singapore, and Russia, which he say have high social discipline and low public dissent. (Bıró-Nagy 2017, p. 36, Buzogány 2017, p. 1308) These countries, according to Orbán, are able to put the interests of the collective ahead of the individual, and therefore combine both an authoritarian government system with economic growth distributed equally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;illiberalism-in-action&#34;&gt;Illiberalism in Action&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lliberalism&amp;rsquo;s implementation, however, worked far beyond its stated goals towards prosperity and the leveling of elites. There were two dimensions to the realization of illiberal democracy in Hungary, first is the economic dimension, and second is the political dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the economic realm, a strong set of economic nationalist policies were implemented which Orbán referred to as “civic conservatism.” This stemmed directly from the disappointment with capitalism in Hungary following the fall of the socialist regime. (Bıró-Nagy 2017, p. 35) This meant a concerted effort to reaquire the shares lost during the rounds of privatization in critical sectors such as banking, telecommunication, and energy. This also included new taxes for foreign businesses operating in Hungary. This was all in an effort to strengthen the middle class and protect the country from external influences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another economic policy was a “workfare” targeting the “unproductive” sectors of the populations such as the rural, poor, and Roma. (Buzogány 2017, p. 1313) Orban himself envisions a “work-based” society where those who cannot or do not want to work will be forfeit certain rights. Politically, the Orbán’s party has gone to great lengths to establish itself as the primary party in power, first through a constitutional change, and further attempts to influence society even within formal democratic procedures. When Fidesz first entered power, it won a supermajority, and with that the power to change the constitution in the country. It quickly worked to change the “Fundamental Law,” greatly diminishing the independence of the judicial system which had extensive powers even within Europe as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was followed up by the establishment of a new department with oversight over the media in the Hungary and domination of news sources with pro- government views. Furthermore, NGOs and civil society groups, especially those with foreign support were repressed, characterized by Orbán as foreign agents undermining Hungarian sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this led to the EU’s criticism of Hungary’s democratic backslide, which only led to Hungary further being alienated from the EU and deepening Euroskepticism in the country. After EU’s criticism, Russo-Hungarian ties strengthened and Orbán began to speak more publicly about his admiration for the Russian state. A diversification in Hungary’s economic ties was followed up soon after, from depending on Western states towards expanding their ties with Eastern states such as Russia and China. This can be exemplified in Orbán’s quote that “While we sail under a Western flag, it is an Eastern wind that blows in the world economy.” (Buzogány 2017, p. 36)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary’s backsliding in democracy was not a sudden shift that was unexpected, but rather based on historical experience and a political culture which resulted from it. The disappointment with the democratic process and capitalism combined with the political culture led to a wave of right-wing nationalism when a political crisis within the socialist party struck. Illiberal democracy is a conservative project that rejects the liberal democracy that many Hungarians blame for the extremely inequality and economic downturn in post-communist Hungary, and played on populist fears of an economic elite. This illiberal democracy’s implementation in Hungary has led to not just an economic nationalist project, but the start to a deterioration of democratic institutions which all put Fidesz at the core of Hungarian politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bıró-Nagy, András (2017). “Illiberal democracy in Hungary: The social back- ground and practical steps of building an illiberal state”. In: Illiberal democ- racies in the EU: the Visegrad Group and the risk of disintegration, pp. 31– 44.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buzogány, Aron (2017). “Illiberal democracy in Hungary: authoritarian diffusion or domestic causation?” In: Democratization 24.7, pp. 1307–1325.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magyar, Kornélia (2010). The extreme-right in Hungary after the 2010 elections. Friedrich-Ebert-Stiftung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/illiberalhungary/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Democracy in the Chinese Context</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/chinesedemocracy/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 20:50:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/chinesedemocracy/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/chinesedemocracy/ -&lt;p&gt;The People’s Republic of China’s ruling party, the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) consistently and proudly calls itself a democracy. However, in the West, it is obvious to see that there is little parallel in what is defined as a democracy here, and the structure in China seen today. Equally puzzling, the democratic movements in China from the Democracy Wall movement in 1978-1979 to the Tiananmen Square protests in 1989 were cracked down on specifically with the rhetoric of democracy by the Chinese government. A closer look at the Chinese government’s ideology and their understanding of democracy reveals that there is an internal logic there within all of these parties which use the common language of “democracy.” The content of the language used shows that what “democracy” means to different groups varies wildly, and that using solely the term “democracy” may not be enough to describe fully the sheer diversity seen in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;meaning-of-democracy-in-china&#34;&gt;Meaning of Democracy in China&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democracy is rendered in Chinese as &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/009770049602200403&#34;&gt;“minzhu”&lt;/a&gt;, which is composed of two characters: “min” and “zhu.” In Chinese language, a single character can have many varying definitions, and these characters are no different. Depending on context and usage, the character “min” can mean “common people” as opposed to “officials”, the “people” as opposed to “class enemies,” or the “individual” as opposed to the “collective.” Similarly, the character for “zhu” can mean either “master,” which means being in charge, or “primary” which does not necessarily mean in charge, but taken as the most important topic of concern. This much variation in the basic components of the word for “democracy” means that in Chinese culture, democracy can be interpreted quite differently by different groups, or even the same group but at different points in time. It makes sense then to contrast the Western conception of “democracy” to the Chinese conception of “minzhu,” as ideas which are clearly related and in constant discussion with one another, but nonetheless fundamentally differ from one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internal diversity and discussion surrounding China’s own discussion of democracy is also seen in the multiple democracy movements from 1978 to 1989. While the CCP had a consistent view how its institutions were democratic, as a result of differing definitions of what democracy entailed by other groups in China, under differing influences, there have been multiple incidents all revolving around the idea of “democracy.” For example, in the Democracy Wall movement from 1978 to 1979, was formed from a coalition of a diverse set of actors each operating under their conception of democracy, ranging from orthodox Marxist to and Western human rights’ standpoints, each with influence from Chinese traditional ideas of rights and the relation between the people and government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional Chinese idea which influenced most of these discussions was the idea of “minben,” which along with the previous character of “min” put together with “ben” which means “root” or “basis.” This means to put the welfare of the people as the basis of the government. There is inherently a paternalist tone to the idea as it assumes a dichotomy between the state and the people, with the state held responsible for the well being of the people, without any suggestion of the people holding the government accountable, or having any role in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The party’s conception of democracy was clearly influenced by both Marxist ideology and minben, by both using the Leninist language of the vanguard party, and also that their role was purely in the interest of the people’s welfare, albeit without their participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The democracy movements which challenged this idea of democracy, also differed quite a bit how they thought of democracy within themselves. The Marxist elements of the Democracy Wall movement, understood “minzhu” as consistently not of the “common people” being “primary,” but rather them being the “masters.” This would be achieved through an implementation of Paris Commune style communism or Yugoslavian communism where the workers managed their own affairs, and officials were elected, not appointed. Another idea was to have a multiparty system, but each operating under the common interest of the people, differing only in the strategy of working towards that goal. The influence of traditional Confucian values of “harmony” and “collective welfare” can be seen here as they formulated their arguments as not promoting the individual and their rights, but rather to have the collective wellbeing of society be the ultimate interest of these parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tiananmen Square movement of 1989 had some continuities with the Democracy Wall movement, such as their nationalism and working towards the ultimate well being of society as a whole. However, their discourse notably took on much more Western conceptions of democracy. For example, the topic of “human rights,” which was an idea rarely used in Chinese discourse, was prominent in this movement. They argued that true democracy was done through having procedures in place to have the people hold the government accountable, and ensuring that the government worked to uphold their human rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the discussion of “democracy” in China is nebulous, often shifting according to the time, and under differing influences such as Marxism, Western human rights discourse, and traditional Confucianism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-partys-criticism&#34;&gt;The Party’s Criticism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese Communist Party identified these movements and their deviations from the CCP’s definition of democracy to be dangerous, therefore worked relentlessly to criticize them. The most basic differentiation they created to counter these arguments was between “socialist democracy” and “bourgeois democracy.” They argued that what makes socialist democracy superior to bourgeois democracy, Western liberal democracy, was class. Under a Marxist framework, everything has a class element to them, democracy included. In a socialist democracy, the party acting as a vanguard party only has the people’s interest, and no interests of its own. However, the party also does not blindly follow the people. It is this way that the party is democratic, and procedures have no role in determining if a system is democratic or not, because the procedures can work for or against the people’s interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore as a vanguard party, they are intrinsically linked to the state, and their position as the sole ruling party guarantees stability and security, and through that, the ability to work in the interests of the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another element of socialist democracy is that since the workers have ownership of the means of production, that guarantees their social justice better than bourgeois democracy could where there is private ownership of the means of production. This is since private ownership of the means of production would inevitably lead to a bourgeois class and an undemocratic institution in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through these arguments, the CCP justified their crushing of democratic movements in the country. They argued that a bipartisan Marxist democracy as was suggested by some in the Democracy Wall movement would undermine the CCP’s position as the vanguard party, and along with it the very existence of the state which would lead to more chaos. They also criticized emulating the multiparty democracies of Western countries, because while they seem to represent different interest groups, in practice, they have a common interest in promoting capitalism, and the only group that gets represented ends up being the bourgeois as they are the only group which have the resources to run for office and pay for campaigns in a multiparty electoral system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly a decade later, the CCP would use similar arguments to justify their crackdown on the Tiananmen Square protestors, along with the further criticism of their demand for a more procedural democracy with special protections for human rights. However, the CCP argued that what rights are afforded to the people are dependent on the conditions of the state. Therefore, what human rights exist are developed alongside the development of the state&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;comparison-to-western-democracy&#34;&gt;Comparison to Western Democracy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the criticism of their internal democratic movements, the party also criticized Western liberal democracy, which many of these movements were influenced by, and took inspiration from. As mentioned before, Western liberal democracy is characterized by two main elements: procedures and rights. Democracy exists to protect the natural rights of the people from the government, and this is done through a set of procedures to the government accountable to the will of the people. Both of these processes were criticized by the CCP within a Marxist framework which also took influence from traditional Chinese political tradition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the idea of “natural rights” was criticized for it led to the develop ment of a bourgeois capitalist mode of production, and could not guarantee social justice or equitable distribution of wealth. Socialist democracy guaranteed both social justice and equitable distribution through public ownership. In addition, “rights” in Chinese political tradition derived from the government’s obligation to the people, rather than any inherent human existence. Thus, rights are granted by the government for the purpose of better functioning of itself, rather than in the Western context where rights are granted to protect the people the government. Therefore, the CCP can justify the limiting of certain rights if it meant the healthy functioning of the government, and by extension, the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, prominent aspects of Western liberal democracy such as a parliamentary system, or electoral process were criticized. The parliamentary system was criticized for only allowing for a coordination between the ruling class, and the electoral process existing only to provide legitimacy to the perpetuation of their interests in the political realm. Thereby, the party justified their stance against the emulation of Western democracy, and the further criticize the democratic movements within the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democracy is a highly variable concept, and difficult to nail down in the Chinese context. Not only does the concept of democracy (minzhu) differ highly from how it is defined in the West, even within the country among different groups it is defined differently depending on their influences from other traditions whether it be Marxism, Chinese tradition, or Western tradition. This tension between the differing interpretations of what democracy is has led to the formation of several democratic movements in China, and their subsequent crushing by the CCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it is important to note that these “democratic” movements were advocating for a model of democracy that is notably different to what is traditionally seen as “democracy” in the West. If the goal is to achieve democracy in China, then there should be a shift from seeing these movements unqualifiedly as “democratic” to a term which is able to better capture their content. In the West, the definition of democracy is consistent and has a firm grounding in Western liberal tradition, however in China, it is not consistent, and what is “democracy” may shift from one movement to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sources-and-further-reading&#34;&gt;Sources and Further Reading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan, Andrew J (1986). Chinese democracy. Univ of California Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun, Yan (1995). The Chinese reassessment of socialism, 1976-1992. Princeton University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/chinesedemocracy/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>KMT Factional Politics on Democratization in Taiwan</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/factionstaiwan/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 20:45:47 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/factionstaiwan/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/factionstaiwan/ -&lt;p&gt;Ever since the Kuomintang (KMT) fled to the island of Taiwan in 1949, it has been the sole party in power until moves towards democratization in the 80s. While the present liberal democracy status of Taiwan is unquestionable, there are still remnants from the old party rule which prevents further democratization in Taiwanese politics. Every step of the way from the establishment of the Republic of China in Taiwan, to its eventual democratization, local factionalism has been a key element in the KMT’s hold on power and electoral strategy. It has been argued that while the support for the Democratical Progress Party (DPP) party, the current party in power, is based in ideology, the KMT’s support is still “faction based,” as in that it relies on local factional mobilization to elect officials. (Bosco 1994, p. 31) Despite its undemocratic nature, as it does not rely on the democratic process to get officials elected, in fact this was one of the factors which helped the Taiwanese political system to democratize since the party was willing to let political change happen knowing it had the network necessary to get their politicians elected. (Bosco 1994, p. 30) However, in the modern day, the KMT has still yet to become a “normal” party, since it still holds on to its strong local factional presence and mobilization strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;faction&#34;&gt;Faction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The definition for “faction” used here, is that of Bosco’s study into the fac- tions of Taiwan, where he notes it to be a “political conflict group that are not corporate and whose members are recruited by a leader on diverse princi- ples.” (Bosco 2016, p. 1) Furthermore a “local faction” is a set of interpersonal networks that function, for political purposes, in the local as opposed to the national arena. (Chen 2016, p. 224) These factions originate from pre-existing networks in the local level even before the KMT’s escape to the island. But they formed into existence around when the very first elections were held at the local level. They are usually limited to the county and township level, because the KMT wanted to eliminate any factionalism greater than the county level. These factions then mobilize votes in the village level through local leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the KMT first moved to Taiwan, they were an outsider to the island and had no connection with the locals. As a way to build legitimacy and connect with the local population, the KMT co-opted the local loose personal relations which already existed on the local level to mobilize them to vote in their favor in elections. As return, the KMT would provide various economic benefits. (Chen 2016) It also provided a look of democracy for the KMT government which was in alliance with other democratic states. (Cheng 1989, p. 478)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Factional leaders are nearly all members of the KMT, and are more cohesive than factions than other countries. (Bosco 2016, p. 2) Ever since their co- option, local factions have been critical to sustaining the KMT rule on the island. During the latter half of the KMT rule on the island, nearly 60% of KMT nominated candidates were faction affiliated. The members of the faction can be expected to receive rewards should they be victorious, especially in terms of jobs which is the most common patronage type. (Bosco 2016, p. 8) There are also cases of vote buying wherein a rural voter may receive gifts, including cash in hongbaos, “ren envelopes,” for supporting a certain candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this worked to establish a strictly local system of clientelism between the KMT party and local leaders, as well the voters they mobilize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;transition-to-democracy&#34;&gt;Transition to Democracy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The client system worked well to consolidate the KMT’s political power over Taiwanese society, which in turn was instrumental in its path to economic development. (Cheng 1989, p. 480) Their GDP was growing at an average rate of 9% from 1960 to 1980. This led to a new middle class, but not only that the demographics of those with economic power were now mainly the Taiwanese, not the mainlander demographic of those in political power. (Cheng 1989, p. 483) This new demographic educated in the social sciences, demanded for a liberal democracy to take place in the Taiwanese government structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to these demands, the KMT attempted to co-opt the activists by ceding some political reforms such as more supplementary elections. The KMT still banned opposition parties, and to prevent the opposition forces from organizing themselves into parties, they instead tried to send them through the KMT system as new candidates. (Cheng 1989, p. 487) This might have backfired however as this meant that soon enough there were Taiwanese political elites who had much more of a sense of a separate Taiwanese identity than a Chinese one. Through a careful and complicated bargaining process between the growing opposition and the KMT, eventually the first competitive election in Taiwan’s history was held in 1986.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another concession made by the KMT was to grant the local factions to form island-wide alliance whereas before they were restricted to the local counties and townships. This led to the development of factions around Taiwan which did not necessarily have to align themselves with the KMT, but which nonetheless still generally kept their old networks. (Chen 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;current-day&#34;&gt;Current Day&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current day, the local electoral advantages that the KMT enjoyed is still felt today. When it comes to island-wide elections, it is often the leading opposition party, the Democratic Progress Party (DPP), who has the advantage since it relies on ideological and political appeal to gain voters. Those who have the education to think about political and ideological issues to vote are therefore likely to vote DPP. Factions also tend to be weaker in cities, since the social networks that a voter is tied is much more complex than in villages or counties. (Bosco 1994, p. 45-6) Both of these factors lead to the DPP appealing to urban voters in general who tend to be more educated and less susceptible to factionalism. Therefore the KMT has to rely more on its local factions to stay in power and hold on to seats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A consequence of its relationship has been that factions has used its new- found independence, since it is no longer restricted to a locality, to gain a lever- age over the KMT. (Rigger 2005, p. 320 This means that the KMT is increasing relying on self-interested factions to hold on to power, and further strengthening the patron-client relationships. The KMT, during the 1991 National Assembly elections, even strunk the size of electoral districts, to lend more power to the factional mobilization strategy. (Bosco 1994, p. 59) This further strengthens the factions and local interests, and shows the KMT’s reliance on these factions for votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite Taiwan being a vibrant democracy today with competitive elections, the parties are still not on completely equal ground as they approach elections. The KMT’s political strategies from its party dictatorship era still hold in to- day’s elections. Factional mobilization strategy that relies on a patron-client system with a dominant party is even more important to the KMT now. This means that during elections, the strategy for both parties look different from each other. The DPP uses the democratic process of political campaigns and ideological arguments to win over voters in urban districts, while the KMT’s pol- itics are tied down to pleasing local leaders and giving out tributes to maintain their support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still further changes which could be had to improve the democratic institutions in Taiwan. The KMT has relied on the factions to stay in power despite strong opposition up until now. But the system which relies on is one filled with corruption rather than a clear democratic process. Until the point in which the KMT can get rid of its factional reliance and compete with the DPP or any other party on the same level, the democratic transition away from the KMT is still not fully done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bosco, Joseph (1994). “Faction versus ideology: Mobilization strategies in Tai- wan’s elections”. In: The China Quarterly 137, pp. 28–62.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bosco, Joseph (2016). “Taiwan factions: guanxi, patronage, and the state in local politics”. In: The Other Taiwan, 1945-92. Routledge, pp. 124–154.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen, Ming-tong (2016). “Local factions and elections in Taiwan’s democrati- zation”. In: Taiwan’s electoral politics and democratic transition: Riding the third wave. Routledge, pp. 174–192.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheng, Tun-jen (1989). “Democratizing the quasi-Leninist regime in Taiwan”. In: World politics 41.4, pp. 471–499.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rigger, Shelley (2005). “Grassroots electoral organization and political reform in the ROC on Taiwan and Mexico”. In: The Awkward Embrace. Routledge, pp. 325–340.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/factionstaiwan/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>中國臺灣國語發音差異</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/standard_chinese/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 21:49:37 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/standard_chinese/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/standard_chinese/ -&lt;p&gt;為何臺灣國語與中國普通話有他們現在的差異?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每人都知道中國的中文與臺灣的中文不同，最明顯的是在臺灣人們的翹舌音和平舌音的差別不大。然而這樣的差別不是我今日討論的，而是為何兩者的標準中文有現今的差異。簡單的解釋是「就是因為它們分開那麼多年，肯定有一些差別」，然而如此解釋還不完整。因此我要提出更完整的解釋。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;首先，國語和普通話何時分開了？標準國語的發音1928年出現了，當時的語言學家以北京音為基礎，不過他們也為了訂一些字標準音開會了。這些語言學家注重韻書和音變規律訂發音。其次，1949以後，中國已經有一個新政府。這個共產黨訂定國音時也以北京話為基底，不過卻更注重北方的口語發音。
舉一個例子，「微」這個字的古代發音國際音標上是「/mʉi/」。假如便用語音演變的規律，現代官話的發音應該是「ㄨㄟˊ」，因而民國訂定的發音是「ㄨㄟˊ」。但北方方言將字的二聲變成一聲，因此中共的標準音卻是「ㄨㄟ」。
1949以來，臺灣與中國的歷史也分開了，所以他們的語言也發展得不同。有最大差異的地方是科技，因為很多從國外來的技術詞必須要被翻譯，而且既然兩者已經分開了，他們以不同的詞翻譯。比如，在中國標準詞「網絡」，但在臺灣他們說「網路」，或者是臺灣的「軟體」是中國的「軟件」．
由此可見臺灣與中國的中文差異歷史又長又复杂．&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/standard_chinese/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Postmodernity and Ideological Thinking</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/postmodernity_and_loneliness/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 20:27:38 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/postmodernity_and_loneliness/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/postmodernity_and_loneliness/ -&lt;p&gt;The postmodern world has made us lonely and more susceptible to ideological thinking. Furthermore, ideological thinking and its effects are unnoticed as a result of ideologies becoming invisible to itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With coming of the modern world, our attitude shifted to a belief in progress, development over time, and most importantly, a sense of control over progression. Things such as objective reality where there is a cause and a measurable effect as a result. Even if one did not personally observe these relations, others such as experts could be trusted to discover it and publish it. To aid in this progress, standardization of concepts such as space or time across the world, and agreement on those standards by different people around the world developed. Essentially, the attitude was that we inhabited the same world. Over time however, this attitude changed as progress, fueled by a rise in globalization and capitalism, accelerated beyond our control. Our attitude shifted from certainty to uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;postmodernity&#34;&gt;Postmodernity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalism was vital for the development from modernity to postmodernity, indeed it was responsible for the modern world in the first place as well. In this instance however, the capitalist force for new markets abroad and looser government controls led to accelerated globalization and an interconnectedness that detached local lives and brought them in contact with the global world. In this process, capitalism gave way for the modern attitudes of individuality and control over one’s life in each locality, and further gave them the tools to exercise this attitude through the capitalist system. As more and more localities are brought into globality as a result of capitalist expansion, and their individual control expands in some sense, but the concept of cause and effect relations making up the certainty of the modern world paradoxically unravels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not a linear development from control to a lack thereof per se, but rather the acceleration of control to so many different actors which only worked to collectively diminish their control as a result of each person being subject everyone else’s decisions. Control over certain aspects of life has risen, but at the cost of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dynamic of imbalanced control over different domains alongside the ever-accelerating globalization leads to the breakdown of the shared world built by the modern world. With the advent of the internet especially, one has the freedom to output whatever information they would like to, and the choice to consume the information they want to be exposed to as well. But as that choice accelerates with billions of people around the world outputting information as well as absorbing it, the overwhelming amount of content leads to a fragmentation of the world between the individual and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;thinking&#34;&gt;Thinking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here Hannah Arendt’s idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://aeon.co/essays/for-hannah-arendt-totalitarianism-is-rooted-in-loneliness&#34;&gt;loneliness&lt;/a&gt; is useful for analyzing what this does to our psyche. Loneliness is felt when one lacks “standards of thought” and “reality of experience.” Standards of thought is means by which truth and falsehood is distinguished. “Reality of experience” is the ability to distinguish between reality and fantasy through experience. When one is unsure of what is true, and unable to perceive their own experiences as reality, they feel lonely as there is a disconnect from others on the most basic things such as truth and reality. Without these faculties and a society which they can trust, they turn to ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideological thinking arises from, and deepens loneliness despite its apperance to fulfill this lack. Ideology by its definition is an internally logical system of ideas. These ideas provide the framework for interpreting the chaos of an uncertain world. Ideological thinking, through its internal logic, provides the standard of thought to judge trueness. The reality of experience is abandoned for a “realer” reality that can only be perceived through ideological thinking. Experience no longer becomes a valid medium to judge reality through unless it is experience which is filtered through the ideology’s internal logic and perceived to be in line with the reality expected, not reality experienced. But a critical factor missing in the equation of ideological thinking is connection with others. Ideological thinking does not help one connect with others, it deepens disconnect through even further isolation from others&amp;rsquo; experience of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;recognition&#34;&gt;Recognition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a mistake to say that the current world is a post-ideology world as some might claim. This age is more ideological than ever and with it becomes an ever increasing disconnect between people and an ever more fracturing of world experienced. But the difference is that ideology is now more much subtle in its presentation. It is no longer sees even itself as an ideology, but simply the nature state of the world. An ideology unable to recognize itself as an ideology is the most dangerous because it becomes difficult to argue against one’s reality rather than simply an idea that they hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanisms behind how ideologies forgot themselves as ideologies is still unclear to me, but I suspect it has to do with the failure of the two biggest clear ideological threats to liberalism in the 20th century. Both fascism and communism failed to overcome the liberal world order and without an Other to distinguish itself from, it lost its own identity as an ideology, and understood itself to be the natural order of things&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/postmodernity_and_loneliness/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Critique of Asian Identity in the US</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/asianidentity/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/asianidentity/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/asianidentity/ -&lt;p&gt;Asia is a Western notion. Etymologically it is theorized to have come from a Hittite &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Asia#Etymology&#34;&gt;word&lt;/a&gt; meaning “Northwest Anatolia” which was eventually borrowed into Greek from where it spread throughout Europe. From its root, it inherently comes from the perspective of the West looking East. Asia is not a concept born out of Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea of “Asia” eventually found its way to the U.S. where it became a racialized concept denoting everyone hailing from the massive continent of Asia as they imagined it. Especially East Asians would form the popular imagination of what an Asian was, as their presence in both population figures and culture was much greater than other Asian ethnicities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;east-asians&#34;&gt;East Asians&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What results from this attitude over time is the acceptance of that label by the East Asians in the U.S. The power of being constantly perceived as Asian by others was so strong that East Asians began to perceive themselves as simply Asian rather than their particular ethnic identities. It is not uncommon to hear East Asians or those who are identified as having East Asian features to identify themselves firstly as “Asian” before their ethnic identity. This is the basis for the Asian-American identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also not uncommon to see these Asian-Americans being proud of that identity, as well as identify commonalities amongst themselves. It makes sense of course, East Asian cultures have historically tended towards culturally assimilating themselves to Chinese Confucian culture, leading to similar values and cultural ideas. The problem however is that this identity is built on a foundation that holds East Asia as Asia as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the US, a major consequence is the homogenization of what Asian cultures are, as they are defined in the dictionary: Cultures originating from the continent of Asia. The hegemony of East Asians over the term “Asia”, and the coherence of that identity amongst them leads onlookers to make a mental connection going from the term “Asia” immediately to “East Asia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mongolians&#34;&gt;Mongolians&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This poses yet another contradiction for Mongolians-Americans. Because the Mongolian phenotypic features are similar to that of East Asians, Mongolians are also widely perceived as “Asian” by others. In fact, for a time the term &lt;a href=&#34;http://aleph0.clarku.edu/huxley/SM3/GeoDis.html&#34;&gt;“Mongoloid”&lt;/a&gt; was used to group the peoples of Asia and Pacific Islands together. Yet, the culture that comes to mind when the term “Asian” is said is completely contrary to the reality of Mongolian culture. It is ironic for Mongolians to be identified with the East Asian cultures that saw them historically as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hua%E2%80%93Yi_distinction&#34;&gt;antithesis&lt;/a&gt; to their culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with what happened with the East Asians, the constant perception of being Asian by others, not just from the dominant group in the US now but even other East Asians, has resulted in the adoption of the Asian-American identity by Mongolian-Americans. It is no wonder that Mongolian-Americans who grew up in the US under the framework of an Asian-American identification choose to seek closer ties with those of other East Asian ethnicities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to seek closer cultural ties with East Asians does not make sense. Mongolian culture is not rooted in Confucian culture. Mongolian culture is not rooted in sedentary civilization. Mongolian culture at its core is closer to traditional cultures of Central Asia and their history. The concepts of Asia and Asian-American have largely blinded the Mongolian-Americans to their roots and where they seek connection. East Asia is fundamentally different from Central Asia and should not be confused under the homogenizing effects of the term “Asia.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;alternatives&#34;&gt;Alternatives&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are problems which have already been noticed and talked about extensively in the Asian community. However the alternative that they bring up is the further diversification of the term “Asian” in the popular imagination of the US. They see the diversity of the Asian continent, then the homogenization how the word “Asia” is imagined, and seek to bring the two closer together through more representation and more efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as demonstrated in the introductory paragraphs, the mere idea of Asia itself is inappropriate and fundamentally was constructed under a Western perspective. Home to such a wide ranging and completely separate cultures, to assign a single label that makes sense is simply impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I argue for is instead to scrap the entire concept of Asia. There simply should not be a word that refers to the continent of Asia beyond a geographical context. Even then it does not even function properly as a geographic word. The root of the problem we face is that it has extended beyond a geographical term to a cultural and racial one. Instead, regional grouping of the nations inhabiting Asia should be advocated for. There are already well established groupings that have a basis in culture and history such as the previously mentioned East Asia, but also Central Asia or Southeast Asia. This has the benefit of both being useful as being broad enough to be used as basic grouping but specific enough to not lead to illogical cultural groupings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, this is not to oppose the currently existing Asian-American identity as it currently stands as a grouping of East Asians. Since this Asian-American identity has a historical basis and common experience that ties them together. However, the word at the root, Asia, should not be a word that denotes the identity of an entire continent, because the identities are specific but the word is not.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/asianidentity/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 