<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches on Dulguun Gantumur</title>
    <link>https://dgantu.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researches on Dulguun Gantumur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:31:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dgantu.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Conservatism in Kuomintang Cross-Straits Discourse since Tsai Ing-Wen</title>
      <link>https://dgantu.github.io/research/dynamic_conservatism_in_kmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:31:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgantu.github.io/research/dynamic_conservatism_in_kmt/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The former ruling party of Kuomintang (KMT) in Taiwan has shifted in its policies and role wildly in its history while retaining their core identity and values, a pattern which has been described by some authors as “dynamic conservatism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illiberal Democracy in Hungary</title>
      <link>https://dgantu.github.io/research/hungarian_democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:41:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgantu.github.io/research/hungarian_democracy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hungary has experienced democratic backsliding in recent years, which stands out since it is a country in the EU, located at the center of Europe, and surrounded by strong democracies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy in the Chinese Context</title>
      <link>https://dgantu.github.io/research/democracy_china/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:40:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgantu.github.io/research/democracy_china/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The People’s Republic of China’s ruling party, the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) consistently and proudly calls itself a democracy. However, in the West, it is obvious to see that there is little parallel in what is defined as a democracy here, and the structure in China seen today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMT Factional Politics on Democratization in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://dgantu.github.io/research/kmt_factions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:41:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dgantu.github.io/research/kmt_factions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ever since the Kuomintang (KMT) fled to the island of Taiwan in 1949, it has been the sole party in power until moves towards democratization in the 80s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
