<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Socialism on Dulguun Gantumur</title>
    <link>https://dulguun.xyz/tags/socialism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Socialism on Dulguun Gantumur</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 21:08:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dulguun.xyz/tags/socialism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Illiberal Democracy in Hungary</title>
      <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/illiberalhungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 21:08:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/illiberalhungary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hungary has experienced democratic backsliding in recent years, which stands out since it is a country in the EU, located at the center of Europe, and surrounded by strong democracies. Yet somehow, a strong wave of right-wing parties who openly declare themselves to be against “liberal democracy” has taken hold in the country, in stark contrast to the standard seen in the European Union. The prime minister of this party, Viktor Orbán declared that “illiberal democracy” is the country’s future, which led some to question what exactly this entails, and how such a concept has taken hold in a country surrounded by democracies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democracy in the Chinese Context</title>
      <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/chinesedemocracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 20:50:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/chinesedemocracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The People’s Republic of China’s ruling party, the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) consistently and proudly calls itself a democracy. However, in the West, it is obvious to see that there is little parallel in what is defined as a democracy here, and the structure in China seen today. Equally puzzling, the democratic movements in China from the Democracy Wall movement in 1978-1979 to the Tiananmen Square protests in 1989 were cracked down on specifically with the rhetoric of democracy by the Chinese government. A closer look at the Chinese government’s ideology and their understanding of democracy reveals that there is an internal logic there within all of these parties which use the common language of “democracy.” The content of the language used shows that what “democracy” means to different groups varies wildly, and that using solely the term “democracy” may not be enough to describe fully the sheer diversity seen in China.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
