<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dulguun Gantumur</title>
    <link>https://dulguun.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dulguun Gantumur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 08:16:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dulguun.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Postmodernity and Ideological Thinking</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/postmodernity_and_loneliness/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 20:27:38 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/postmodernity_and_loneliness/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/postmodernity_and_loneliness/ -&lt;p&gt;The postmodern world has made us lonely and more susceptible to ideological thinking. Furthermore, ideological thinking and its effects are unnoticed as a result of ideologies becoming invisible to itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With coming of the modern world, our attitude shifted to a belief in progress, development over time, and most importantly, a sense of control over progression. Things such as objective reality where there is a cause and a measurable effect as a result. Even if one did not personally observe these relations, others such as experts could be trusted to discover it and publish it. To aid in this progress, standardization of concepts such as space or time across the world, and agreement on those standards by different people around the world developed. Essentially, the attitude was that we inhabited the same world. Over time however, this attitude changed as progress, fueled by a rise in globalization and capitalism, accelerated beyond our control. Our attitude shifted from certainty to uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;postmodernity&#34;&gt;Postmodernity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalism was vital for the development from modernity to postmodernity, indeed it was responsible for the modern world in the first place as well. In this instance however, the capitalist force for new markets abroad and looser government controls led to accelerated globalization and an interconnectedness that detached local lives and brought them in contact with the global world. In this process, capitalism gave way for the modern attitudes of individuality and control over one’s life in each locality, and further gave them the tools to exercise this attitude through the capitalist system. As more and more localities are brought into globality as a result of capitalist expansion, and their individual control expands in some sense, but the concept of cause and effect relations making up the certainty of the modern world paradoxically unravels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not a linear development from control to a lack thereof per se, but rather the acceleration of control to so many different actors which only worked to collectively diminish their control as a result of each person being subject everyone else’s decisions. Control over certain aspects of life has risen, but at the cost of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dynamic of imbalanced control over different domains alongside the ever-accelerating globalization leads to the breakdown of the shared world built by the modern world. With the advent of the internet especially, one has the freedom to output whatever information they would like to, and the choice to consume the information they want to be exposed to as well. But as that choice accelerates with billions of people around the world outputting information as well as absorbing it, the overwhelming amount of content leads to a fragmentation of the world between the individual and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;thinking&#34;&gt;Thinking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here Hannah Arendt’s idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://aeon.co/essays/for-hannah-arendt-totalitarianism-is-rooted-in-loneliness&#34;&gt;loneliness&lt;/a&gt; is useful for analyzing what this does to our psyche. Loneliness is felt when one lacks “standards of thought” and “reality of experience.” Standards of thought is means by which truth and falsehood is distinguished. “Reality of experience” is the ability to distinguish between reality and fantasy through experience. When one is unsure of what is true, and unable to perceive their own experiences as reality, they feel lonely as there is a disconnect from others on the most basic things such as truth and reality. Without these faculties and a society which they can trust, they turn to ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideological thinking arises from, and deepens loneliness despite its apperance to fulfill this lack. Ideology by its definition is an internally logical system of ideas. These ideas provide the framework for interpreting the chaos of an uncertain world. Ideological thinking, through its internal logic, provides the standard of thought to judge trueness. The reality of experience is abandoned for a “realer” reality that can only be perceived through ideological thinking. Experience no longer becomes a valid medium to judge reality through unless it is experience which is filtered through the ideology’s internal logic and perceived to be in line with the reality expected, not reality experienced. But a critical factor missing in the equation of ideological thinking is connection with others. Ideological thinking does not help one connect with others, it deepens disconnect through even further isolation from others&amp;rsquo; experience of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;recognition&#34;&gt;Recognition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a mistake to say that the current world is a post-ideology world as some might claim. This age is more ideological than ever and with it becomes an ever increasing disconnect between people and an ever more fracturing of world experienced. But the difference is that ideology is now more much subtle in its presentation. It is no longer sees even itself as an ideology, but simply the nature state of the world. An ideology unable to recognize itself as an ideology is the most dangerous because it becomes difficult to argue against one’s reality rather than simply an idea that they hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanisms behind how ideologies forgot themselves as ideologies is still unclear to me, but I suspect it has to do with the failure of the two biggest clear ideological threats to liberalism in the 20th century. Both fascism and communism failed to overcome the liberal world order and without an Other to distinguish itself from, it lost its own identity as an ideology, and understood itself to be the natural order of things&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/postmodernity_and_loneliness/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Critique of Asian Identity in the US</title>
        <link>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/asianidentity/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dulguun.xyz/posts/asianidentity/</guid>
        <description>Dulguun Gantumur https://dulguun.xyz/posts/asianidentity/ -&lt;p&gt;Asia is a Western notion. Etymologically it is theorized to have come from a Hittite &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Asia#Etymology&#34;&gt;word&lt;/a&gt; meaning “Northwest Anatolia” which was eventually borrowed into Greek from where it spread throughout Europe. From its root, it inherently comes from the perspective of the West looking East. Asia is not a concept born out of Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea of “Asia” eventually found its way to the U.S. where it became a racialized concept denoting everyone hailing from the massive continent of Asia as they imagined it. Especially East Asians would form the popular imagination of what an Asian was, as their presence in both population figures and culture was much greater than other Asian ethnicities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;east-asians&#34;&gt;East Asians&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What results from this attitude over time is the acceptance of that label by the East Asians in the U.S. The power of being constantly perceived as Asian by others was so strong that East Asians began to perceive themselves as simply Asian rather than their particular ethnic identities. It is not uncommon to hear East Asians or those who are identified as having East Asian features to identify themselves firstly as “Asian” before their ethnic identity. This is the basis for the Asian-American identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also not uncommon to see these Asian-Americans being proud of that identity, as well as identify commonalities amongst themselves. It makes sense of course, East Asian cultures have historically tended towards culturally assimilating themselves to Chinese Confucian culture, leading to similar values and cultural ideas. The problem however is that this identity is built on a foundation that holds East Asia as Asia as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the US, a major consequence is the homogenization of what Asian cultures are, as they are defined in the dictionary: Cultures originating from the continent of Asia. The hegemony of East Asians over the term “Asia”, and the coherence of that identity amongst them leads onlookers to make a mental connection going from the term “Asia” immediately to “East Asia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mongolians&#34;&gt;Mongolians&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This poses yet another contradiction for Mongolians-Americans. Because the Mongolian phenotypic features are similar to that of East Asians, Mongolians are also widely perceived as “Asian” by others. In fact, for a time the term &lt;a href=&#34;http://aleph0.clarku.edu/huxley/SM3/GeoDis.html&#34;&gt;“Mongoloid”&lt;/a&gt; was used to group the peoples of Asia and Pacific Islands together. Yet, the culture that comes to mind when the term “Asian” is said is completely contrary to the reality of Mongolian culture. It is ironic for Mongolians to be identified with the East Asian cultures that saw them historically as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hua%E2%80%93Yi_distinction&#34;&gt;antithesis&lt;/a&gt; to their culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with what happened with the East Asians, the constant perception of being Asian by others, not just from the dominant group in the US now but even other East Asians, has resulted in the adoption of the Asian-American identity by Mongolian-Americans. It is no wonder that Mongolian-Americans who grew up in the US under the framework of an Asian-American identification choose to seek closer ties with those of other East Asian ethnicities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to seek closer cultural ties with East Asians does not make sense. Mongolian culture is not rooted in Confucian culture. Mongolian culture is not rooted in sedentary civilization. Mongolian culture at its core is closer to traditional cultures of Central Asia and their history. The concepts of Asia and Asian-American have largely blinded the Mongolian-Americans to their roots and where they seek connection. East Asia is fundamentally different from Central Asia and should not be confused under the homogenizing effects of the term “Asia.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;alternatives&#34;&gt;Alternatives&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are problems which have already been noticed and talked about extensively in the Asian community. However the alternative that they bring up is the further diversification of the term “Asian” in the popular imagination of the US. They see the diversity of the Asian continent, then the homogenization how the word “Asia” is imagined, and seek to bring the two closer together through more representation and more efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as demonstrated in the introductory paragraphs, the mere idea of Asia itself is inappropriate and fundamentally was constructed under a Western perspective. Home to such a wide ranging and completely separate cultures, to assign a single label that makes sense is simply impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I argue for is instead to scrap the entire concept of Asia. There simply should not be a word that refers to the continent of Asia beyond a geographical context. Even then it does not even function properly as a geographic word. The root of the problem we face is that it has extended beyond a geographical term to a cultural and racial one. Instead, regional grouping of the nations inhabiting Asia should be advocated for. There are already well established groupings that have a basis in culture and history such as the previously mentioned East Asia, but also Central Asia or Southeast Asia. This has the benefit of both being useful as being broad enough to be used as basic grouping but specific enough to not lead to illogical cultural groupings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, this is not to oppose the currently existing Asian-American identity as it currently stands as a grouping of East Asians. Since this Asian-American identity has a historical basis and common experience that ties them together. However, the word at the root, Asia, should not be a word that denotes the identity of an entire continent, because the identities are specific but the word is not.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dulguun.xyz/posts/asianidentity/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 